Dearborn Group Additional Records 5634
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Dearborn Group Additional Records
1974-2017
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Dearborn Group
5634
4.5 cubic feet
4.5 linear ft.
Records (documents), correspondenc.
Records from various corporations that worked closely with the Dearborn Conference Group.
5677192
Biographical / Historical
The Dearborn Conference Group is an organization of directors of Industrial Relations Research Departments in several large U.S. corporations.
The Dearborn Group includes representatives from major corporations in the automotive, chemical, food processing, paper manufacturing, petroleum, petrochemical, steel, telecommunications and textile industries as well as corporate officers with similar responsibilities representing major utilities, the retail trade and an insurance carrier. Their objectives in meeting as a group are the futherance of industrial relations research methodology, information exchange about industrial relations experiences, and the promotion of industrial relations research.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5569: Dearborn Group Records
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
L. Huang, June 30, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 29, 2017
Automobile industry -- Industrial relations -- United States; Chemical industry -- United States; Collective bargaining -- Automobile industry -- United States; Collective bargaining -- Chemical industry -- United States; Collective bargaining -- Paper industry -- United States; Collective bargaining -- Petroleum industry -- United States; Collective bargaining -- Steel industry -- United States; Collective bargaining -- Telecommunication -- United States; Collective bargaining -- Textile industry -- United States; Employee selection -- United States; Employee training directors -- United States; Executive ability -- Testing; Executives -- Training of -- United States; Food industry and trade -- United States; Industrial relations -- Research -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; Job evaluation -- United States; Paper industry -- Industrial relations -- United States; Employees -- Rating of; Personnel directors; Personnel management -- United States; Personnel management -- Research; Petroleum chemicals industry -- Industrial relations -- United States; Petroleum industry -- Industrial relations -- United States; Retail trade -- Industrial relations -- United States; Safety education, Industrial; Steel industry and trade -- Industrial relations -- United States; Telecommunication -- Industrial relations -- United States; Textile industry -- Industrial relations -- United States; Wages -- United States; Dearborn Conference Group
5677192
- The Conference Board, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes reports on: General Research, Manpower Planning, Turnover, Organizational Development, Performance Appraisal, Recruiting, and Selection Procedures.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Includes reports on: General Research, Assessment Procedures, Organizational Structure, Perrsonnel Organization, and Management Training.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes reports on: General Research, Drug and Alcohol Use, Consultation, Training and Development, and Management Development.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Includes reports on: Communication, Recruiting, Equal Employment Opportunity, Selection, Employee Surveys, and Turnover.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Includes reports on: Attitude and Morale, Equal Opportunity, Selection Tests, and Assessment Procedures.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Includes reports on: Personnel Record Systems, Selection Procedures, Attitude and Morale, Organization Structure, and EEO/Career Planning and Counseling,
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes reports on: Quality of Work Life, Organization Structure, Action Planning, Executive Seminar, Labor Negotiations, and Organizational Description Questionnaire.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes reports on: Attitude and Morale, Job Structure, Supervisory Styles, Long Range Planning, Management Development, Assessment Methods, and Research Methodology.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Includes reports on: Communications, Training and Development, and Selection Procedures.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Includes reports on: Consumer Research, Miscellaneous, Training and Development, Selection Procedures, and Selection Tests.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Includes reports on: Training and Development, Career Planning and Counseling, Assessment Procedures, Management Development, Productivity, Equal Opportunity, and Drug and Alcohol Abuse.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Includes reports on: Equal Opportunity, Training and Development, Work Environment, Productivity, Selection Tests, and Long Range Planning.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Includes reports on: Long Range Planning, Social Responsibility, Organization Structure, General Research, and Employment Stabitility.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Includes reports on: Assessment Procedures, College Recruiting, Management Development, and Performance Appraisals.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Includes reports on: Management Development, CRT Furniture, Job Structure, and Selection Tests.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Includes reports on: Classification of High Potential Managers, and Female Managers.
- Dearborn Conference Reports, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Includes reports on: Attitude Surveys, Organizational Effectiveness and Research, Selection, Career Planning.
- Dearborn Group SP '86, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Reports, Group History
- Dearborn Group 11/86, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Reports
- Dearborn Spr 1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Meeting Reports
- Dearborn - Fall 87, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Dearborn Spring 88, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Dearborn Fall 1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Dearborn SP 89, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Dearborn Fall '89, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Dearborn SP 90, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Dearborn - Fall '90, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Dearborn SP 91, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Catalogue, Reports
- 1991 Dearborn Group Activity Reports "Fall" (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Dearborn 1992 Spring (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Meeting Notes, Job Analysis
- Dearborn 1992 Spring (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Meeting Notes
- Dearborn - Fall 1992 (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Catalogues, Meeting Notes
- Dearborn - Fall 1992 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Catalogue, Notes
- Dearborn Activity Reports Fall 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Dearborn Activity Reports Fall 1993 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Literature, Reports
- Spring 1993 Dearborn Reports (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Spring 1993 Dearborn Reports (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Dearborn Group Activity Reports Spring 1994 (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Dearborn Group Activity Reports Spring 1994 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Dearborn Activity Reports Fall 1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Dearborn Spring 95, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Dearborn Fall '95 (Folder 1 of 2), 1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Dearborn Fall '95 (Folder 2 of 2), 1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Presentation Notes
- Dearborn Spring 96, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Reports, Notes
- Dearborn: Fall '96, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Presentation Notes, Reports
- Dearborn Spring 1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Dearborn 10/97, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Dearborn Spring 1998 (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Conference Reports
- Dearborn Spring 1998 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Dearborn Fall '98, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Inventory, Reports
- Dearborn Spring 1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Biographies, Reports
- Dearborn Fall 1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Dearborn Spring 2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Dearborn - Fall 2000 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- 2001 Spring (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Workshop note, catalogue
- 2001 Spring (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Reports, Catalogues
- Dearborn Fall 2001 (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Dearborn Fall 2001 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Reports, Catalogue
- 2002 Spring (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 16)
- 2002 Spring (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Reports, Pamphlet
- Dearborn Fall 2002 (Folder1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Dearborn Fall 2002 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Catalogue, Performance Reports
- 2003 Spring (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Reports, Slides
- Dearborn Fall 2003 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 2004 Fall (Box 4, Folder 6)
- 2005 Spring (Box 4, Folder 7)
- 2005 Fall (Box 4, Folder 8)
- 2006 Spring (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Slides, Reports
- Dearborn Fall 2006 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Reports, Overview Reports
- 2007 Spring (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Catalogues, Reports
- 2007 Fall (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Presentation Slides, Reports
- 2008 Spring (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Reports, Presentation Slides
- 2008 Spring (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Presentation Slides, Catalogue
- 2008 Fall (Box 4, Folder 15)
- 2009 Spring (Box 4, Folder 16)
- 2009 Fall (Box 4, Folder 17)
- 2010 Spring (Box 4, Folder 18)
- 2010 Fall (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Dearborn Spring 2011 Las Vegas, NV (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Conference Report, Reports
- Dearborn Fall 2011 San Diego (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Folder
- Dearborn - Spring 2012 Alexandria, VA (Box 4, Folder 22)
- 2012 Fall (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Dearborn Spring 2013 3M St. Paul MN (Box 4, Folder 24)
- 2013 Fall (Box 5, Folder 1)
- 2014 Spring (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Dearborn Fall 2014 Ft. Worth TX (Box 5, Folder 3)
- 2015 Fall (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Slide Summary, Reports
- Dearborn Spring 2016 Plano/Dallas 5/12-14/16 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Meeting Summary, Reports
- 2016 Fall Louisville, KY (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Meeting Agenda, Summary
- Dearborn Admin, 1997-2004 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Admin List
- Alumni - Inquiry, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Letters
- Dearborn Alumni Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Biographies
- 2017 Spring Dearborn IBM Armonk, NY (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Meeting Schedule